WHAT, UH
WHAT DID YOU...
WHAT?
I STILL LOVE YOU...
AND I KNOW I PROBABLY SHOULDN'T
EVEN BE HERE TELLING YOU THIS.
I MEAN, YOU'RE WITH CHANDLER,
A GUY I REALLY LIKE...
AND IF YOU SAY HE'S STRAIGHT
I'LL BELIEVE YOU.
AFTER SEEING YOU
THE OTHER NIGHT
I KNEW IF I DIDN'T TELL YOU
I'D REGRET IT
FOR THE REST OF MY LIFE.
LETTING YOU GO WAS
THE STUPIDEST THING
I EVER DID.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE REALLY
NOT SUPPOSED TO BE BACK HERE.
UH, WELL, YOU KNOW, I'M SORRY.
I KNOW THIS IS THE WRONG TIME
AND THE WRONG PLACE
BUT I HAD TO TELL YOU.
I WANT TO SPEND MY LIFE
WITH YOU.
I WANT TO MARRY YOU.
I WANT TO HAVE KIDS WITH YOU.
OH, MY GOD.
WHY DON'T THEY PUT CHAIRS
BACK HERE?
( yelps )
LOOK, I KNOW THIS IS CRAZY,
BUT... AM I TOO LATE?
WELL, Y...
YES, YOU'RE TOO LATE.
I MEAN, WHERE WAS
ALL THIS THREE YEARS AGO?
WELL, I KNOW,
I WAS AN IDIOT...
AND I TRIED
TO FORGET YOU.
I-I REALLY DID.
YOU KNOW, AFTER WE
HAD LUNCH LAST YEAR
I SPENT SIX
MONTHS IN AFRICA
TRYING TO GET YOU
OUT OF MY HEAD.
WHAT WERE YOU DOING
IN AFRICA?
WORKING WITH BLIND KIDS.
OH... WHAT ARE YOU DOING
TO ME?
OH, LOOK... I'M SORRY,
BUT, UM... IT'S...
THIS IS NOT GOING
TO HAPPEN.
OKAY, THAT'S FINE.
I'LL WALK AWAY, AND I'LL
NEVER BOTHER YOU AGAIN
BUT ONLY... IF YOU TELL ME
THAT CHANDLER'S WILLING
TO GIVE YOU
EVERYTHING I AM.
WELL, HE IS.
YEAH, I MEAN...
MARRIAGE IS ALL
HE TALKS ABOUT.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
IN FACT, I'M THE ONE
THAT'S MAKING HIM WAIT.
YOU ARE?
YEAH.
WHY?
BECAUSE OF THE GOVERNMENT.
♪ SO NO ONE TOLD YOU
LIFE WAS GONNA BE THIS WAY ♪
♪ YOUR JOB'S A JOKE,
YOU'RE BROKE ♪
♪ YOUR LOVE LIFE'S D.O.A. ♪
♪ IT'S LIKE YOU'RE ALWAYS
STUCK IN SECOND GEAR ♪
♪ WHEN IT HASN'T BEEN
YOUR DAY, YOUR WEEK ♪
♪ YOUR MONTH,
OR EVEN YOUR YEAR ♪
♪ BUT I'LL BE THERE FOR YOU ♪
♪ 'CAUSE YOU'RE THERE
FOR ME, TOO. ♪
ISN'T IT INCREDIBLE?
YEAH.
MONICA AND CHANDLER
ARE GETTING MARRIED.
I KNOW. THEY'RE GOING
TO BE SO HAPPY TOGETHER.
OH... I MEAN
TWO BEST FRIENDS
FALLING IN LOVE--
HOW OFTEN
DOES THAT HAPPEN?
NOT THAT OFTEN.
NO.
I'M SO HAPPY FOR THEM.
ME, TOO--
SO HAPPY FOR THEM.
I'M SO HAPPY
AND NOT AT ALL JEALOUS.
OH, NO.
OH, GOD, DEFINITELY.
NOT JEALOUS.
MM-MMM.
( chuckles )
I MEAN,
I'M PROBABLY 98% HAPPY
MAYBE TWO PERCENT JEALOUS...
AND, I MEAN,
WHAT'S TWO PERCENT?
THAT'S NOTHING.
TOTALLY.
( sighs )
I'M LIKE 90%/10%.
YEAH, ME, TOO.
HEY, UH...
HAVE YOU GUYS SEEN CHANDLER?
WELL, NO, BUT YOU KNOW
WHO DID STOP IN HERE
LOOKING FOR YOU?
UM, TENNILLE.
SO, THAT MARRIAGE STUFF
THAT YOU WERE
SAYING YESTERDAY
YOU DON'T REALLY
BELIEVE THAT, DO YOU?
SURE, I DO.
IN FACT, I THINK
THE WHOLE CONCEPT
OF MARRIAGE IS UNNATURAL.
I MEAN, LOOK AT PIGS.
LET'S TAKE A SECOND HERE
AND LOOK AT PIGS.
OKAY, PIGS DON'T MATE
FOR LIFE.
I MEAN, A PIG CAN HAVE, LIKE
A HUNDRED SEXUAL PARTNERS
IN A LIFETIME
AND THAT'S
JUST AN ORDINARY PIG
NOT EVEN A PIG
THAT'S GOOD AT SPORTS.
WAIT A MINUTE.
ARE YOU HONESTLY
TELLING ME
THAT-THAT YOU MAY NEVER
WANT TO GET MARRIED?
WELL, NEVER SAY NEVER,
BUT, YOU KNOW, PROBABLY, UM...
YEAH, NEVER.
OH, MY GOD.
TH-TH-THEN, WHAT
ARE WE EVEN DOING?
WHAT IS THIS?
WHOA, WHOA, WHOA,
WHAT IS ALL THIS PRESSURE?
IS THIS SOME NEW KIND
OF STRATEGY?
WHY DON'T YOU PUT DOWN YOUR COPY
OF THE RULES, HUH, MAN-TRAP?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I GOT TO GO.
( Monica sighs exasperatedly)
IT'S OKAY.
I GOT A PLAN.
WE'RE GOING
TO FIND LOVE.
DEFINITELY.
YEAH, I'M PRETTY CONFIDENT
ABOUT THAT.
THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT
SO EASY
FOR ME TO BE 80% HAPPY
FOR MONICA AND CHANDLER.
IT'D BE NICE TO HAVE
A LITTLE GUARANTEE, THOUGH.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WELL, YOU KNOW, SOME PEOPLE
MAKE DEALS WITH A FRIEND
LIKE, IF NEITHER OF THEM
ARE MARRIED
BY THE TIME THEY'RE 40,
THEY MARRY EACH OTHER.
YOU MEAN A BACKUP?
YEAH, EXACTLY.
YEAH, YEAH, I'VE GOT THAT.
YOU DO?
MM-HMM.
WHO?
JOEY.
JOEY?
YEAH.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
YEAH, I LOCKED HIM IN
YEARS AGO.
WAIT, SO, IF NEITHER
OF YOU ARE MARRIED
BY THE TIME YOU'RE 40
YOU'RE GOING
TO MARRY JOEY?
YEP, WE SHOOK ON IT.
YEAH... BUT BELIEVE ME
THAT IS NOT HOW HE
WANTED TO SEAL THE DEAL.
OH. SERIOUSLY?
OH, YEAH.
I THINK HIS EXACT WORDS WERE...
( clicks tongue/kisses/growls)
CHARMING.
AH, HE'S JUST A BACKUP.
YEAH.
( chuckles )
HEY, MONICA.
HAVE YOU SEEN RACHEL...
OR A MIRROR?
THIS IS FOR MY BOAT.
PRETTY COOL, HUH?
YEAH, IT'S GREAT.
WHOA, WHOA, WHAT'S THE MATTER?
TALK TO THE CAPTAIN.
I'M JUST HAVING
ONE OF THOSE DAYS
WHERE YOU REALIZE YOU'RE
IN A DEAD-END RELATIONSHIP.
CHANDLER GIVING YOU
A HARD TIME, HUH?
IT'S NOT LIKE I WANT
TO GET MARRIED TOMORROW.
IT'S JUST I'D
LIKE TO BELIEVE
THAT I'M IN A RELATIONSHIP
THAT'S GOING SOMEWHERE
THAT I'M NOT JUST
WASTING MY TIME.
WELL, YOU KNOW CHANDLER.
NO, I DON'T
KNOW CHANDLER...
NOT ANYMORE.
IT'S LIKE...
IT'S LIKE
SOMETHING'S CHANGED.
MAYBE YOU CHANGED.
I DIDN'T CHANGE.
MAYBE THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
WHAT?
CHANDLER IS A COMPLEX FELLOW
ONE WHO IS UNLIKELY
TO TAKE A WIFE.
WELL, WHAT DOES HE THINK?
DOES HE THINK I'M JUST GOING
TO WAIT AROUND FOR NOTHING?
MONICA, FACE IT, CHANDLER
IS AGAINST MARRIAGE
AN-AND ALWAYS WILL BE.
YEAH, WELL,
THERE'S SOME PEOPLE
WHO DO WANT
TO MARRY ME.
THERE ARE?
YEAH-- RICHARD.
RI-RI-RICHARD SAID
HE WANTS TO MARRY YOU?
MM-HMM.
CHANDLER'S TELLING YOU
HOW MUCH HE HATES MARRIAGE?
THAT'S RIGHT.
CHANDLER LOVES MARRIAGE!
YOU JUST TOLD ME THAT
HE HATES MARRIAGE
TH-THAT HE'S A...
A COMPLEX FELLOW WHO'S
UNLIKELY TO TAKE A WIFE
TH-THAT HE'S
AGAINST MARRIAGE
AND ALWAYS WILL BE.
YOU GOT THAT FROM WHAT I SAID?
RACH?
HEY, YOU.
HEY.
COME ON IN.
OH, THANK YOU.
HEY, YOU KNOW, I'M SO SORRY
TO HEAR ABOUT YOU AND ELIZABETH.
OH, THANKS.
YEAH, I REALLY THOUGHT
WE'D BE ABLE
TO MAKE IT WORK
BUT, UH... I GUESS IT
JUST WASN'T MEANT TO BE.
YEAH.
LOVE...
IT'S A TRICKY BUSINESS,
ISN'T IT?
I GUESS SO.
SO, WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE MAKE A PACT--
IF YOU AND I ARE BOTH SINGLE
BY THE TIME WE'RE 40
WE GET MARRIED.
I MEAN, WE KNOW EACH OTHER,
WE LIKE EACH OTHER...
I MEAN,
WE'VE ALREADY SLEPT TOGETHER.
SO, YOU KNOW, THERE'LL BE
NO SURPRISES THERE.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
NO, LIKE, WHAT'S THAT?
( laughing )
SO, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
OH, YOU... YOU WANT
ME TO BE YOUR BACKUP?
EXACTLY.
OH, YEAH... I ALREADY HAVE ONE.
WHAT? WHO?
PHOEBE.
PHOEBE?
WAIT A MINUTE.
BUT SHE... BUT SHE JUST...
SHE SAID JOEY IS HER BACKUP.
( laughing ):
OH, I DON'T THINK SO.
ROSS, I JUST HAD A CONVERSATION
WITH HER
AND SHE SAID
THAT SHE AND JOEY MADE A DEAL.
THAT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
I MEAN,
WE HAVE HAD A DEAL FOR YEARS.
WE-WE-WE SHOOK ON IT...
ALTHOUGH, BELIEVE ME, SHE WANTED
TO DO A LOT MORE THAN THAT.
WHERE THE HELL HAVE YOU BEEN?!
I WAS MAKING A COCONUT PHONE
WITH THE PROFESSOR.
( stammering )
RICHARD TOLD MONICA
HE WANTS TO MARRY HER.
WHAT?
YEAH, YEAH.
I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO FIND YOU
TO TELL YOU STOP
MESSING WITH HER
AND MAYBE I WOULD HAVE
IF THESE DAMN BOAT SHOES
WOULDN'T KEEP FLYING OFF!
OH, MY GOD.
I KNOW, THEY SUCK!
HE'S NOT SUPPOSED TO ASK
MY GIRLFRIEND TO MARRY HIM.
I'M SUPPOSED TO DO THAT.
I KNOW!
WELL, WHAT...
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M GOING TO DO?
I'M GOING TO GO OVER THERE,
I'M GOING TO KICK HIS ASS!
WILL YOU HELP ME?
LOOK, CHANDLER, I
DON'T THINK US GETTING
OUR ASSES KICKED
IS A SOLUTION, OKAY?
JUST GO AND FIND MONICA.
YOU'RE RIGHT. OKAY.
YEAH.
I'M GOING TO GET THE RING.
I'M GOING TO GO FIND HER
AND I'M JUST
GOING TO PROPOSE.
OKAY.
OKAY, GO GET HER.
DUDE, DUDE, DUDE.
HUH?
LET ME KNOW
ABOUT THAT COCONUT PHONE.
IT MIGHT BE GOOD
FOR THE BOAT.
( knocking )
HI.
I DON'T WHY I'M HERE.
I DIDN'T ASK.
YOU WANT TO COME IN?
I DON'T KNOW.
OH, OKAY.
WELL, I'LL JUST LEAVE
THE DOOR OPEN
AND GO SIT ON THE COUCH.
CHANDLER IS SUCH AN IDIOT.
DRINK?
YEAH. I'LL HAVE
A SCOTCH ON THE...
ROCKS WITH A TWIST?
I REMEMBER.
YOU START SMOKING CIGARS?
UH...
NO, NO. THAT'S ART.
IF IT BOTHERS YOU,
I CAN PUT MY ART OUT.
NO, THAT'S OKAY.
SO, MONICA...
LET ME ASK YOU
A QUESTION.
YOU KNOW, SINCE
WE BROKE UP
DO YOU EVER...
THINK ABOUT ME?
YEAH, ACTUALLY, I THOUGHT
ABOUT YOU A COUPLE MONTHS AGO.
OH, REALLY?
YEAH, BUT IT'S 'CAUSE
I HAD AN EYE EXAM
AND I DON'T LIKE
MY NEW EYE DOCTOR.
WHO IS IT?
EDWARD NEVSKY.
YEAH, HE'S NO GOOD.
DO YOU EVER THINK ABOUT ME
IN A... NON-EYE-DOCTOR WAY?
NO.
AH.
BECAUSE GETTING OVER YOU
IS THE HARDEST THING
THAT I'VE EVER HAD TO DO
AND I NEVER LET MYSELF
THINK ABOUT YOU.
( no audio )
PHOEBE, YOU PICKED
JOEY AND ROSS?
YOU CANNOT HAVE TWO BACKUPS!
OF COURSE I CAN.
IT'S JUST GOOD SENSE
TO BACK UP YOUR BACKUP.
LOOK, I'VE ALREADY LOST
CHANDLER.
WHAT?
HEY, PHOEBE
WE'RE BOTH YOUR BACKUP?
PHOEBE, HOW COULD YOU
DO THIS TO ME?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU'RE
COMPLAINING ABOUT NOW.
YOU WERE BOTH AWARE
OF THE SITUATION.
NO, WE WEREN'T.
I WAS NOT!
OKAY, THIS KIND OF BACK TALK
IS NOT GOING TO FLY
WHEN WE'RE MARRIED.
PHOEBE, YOU CAN'T HAVE
BOTH OF THEM.
YOU HAVE TO PICK ONE.
PICK ME!
NO, PICK ME!
I DON'T WANT
TO END UP AN OLD MAID.
ALL RIGHT. WELL, LET'S SEE.
ROSS IS A GOOD FATHER,
BUT JOEY HAS A BOAT.
THIS IS HARD.
THIS IS CRAZY.
LOOK, I WANT TO
SWITCH TO RACHEL.
OOH, I WANT TO SWITCH
TO RACHEL, TOO.
NO, JUST WAIT!
YOU GUYS
WAIT, GUYS.
DON'T MAKE ANY RASH DECISIONS,
OKAY?
JUST REMEMBER MY PROMISE:
IF WE GET MARRIED,
THREE TIMES A WEEK.
OH, GOD, PHOEBE.
I'M TALKING
ABOUT MASSAGES.
OH, ALL RIGHT.
( no audio )
ALL RIGHT,
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I KNOW HOW
TO SETTLE THIS.
ALL RIGHT, THIS IS
WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO.
I'M GOING TO WRITE
"JOEY" ON ONE NAPKIN
AND I'M GOING TO WRITE
"ROSS" ON THE OTHER NAPKIN
AND WE ARE GOING
TO PICK ONE
AND THAT PERSON IS
GOING TO BE OUR BACKUP, OKAY?
HERE WE GO.
THAT SOUNDS FAIR.
FINE.
GOOD.
WOO-OO!
PICK ONE.
LEFT.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
"ROSS."
"JOEY."
HMM.
WE SHOULD JUST
SWITCH.
YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
I MISS THIS APARTMENT.
NOW, THIS IS
A GROWN-UP'S APARTMENT.
I SHOULD BE WITH A GROWN-UP.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
YEAH. YOU'RE SAYING YOU NEED
TO BE WITH SOMEONE MORE MATURE.
MAYBE SOMEONE WITH
A LICENSE
TO PRACTICE MEDICINE...
OR A MUSTACHE.
YOU KNOW, LET'S FACE IT.
I'M NOT A KID ANYMORE.
I NEED TO BE WITH SOMEONE
WHO WANTS THE SAME THINGS
THAT I DO.
COMING TO MY PLACE OF WORK
AND TELLING ME
THAT YOU LOVE ME--
I WANT THAT!
TALKING ABOUT PIG SEX
OVER LUNCH--
I DON'T WANT THAT!
I THINK THAT'S FAIR.
"FAIR"? PLEASE, DON'T EVEN TALK
TO ME ABOUT FAIR.
FAIR WOULD HAVE BEEN
YOU WANTING
TO MARRY ME BACK THEN.
OR FAIR WOULD BE
CHANDLER WANTING
TO MARRY ME NOW.
BELIEVE ME,
NOTHING ABOUT THIS IS FAIR.
NOTHING, NOTHING
NOTHING. NOTHING, NOTHING,
NOTHING, NOTHING, NOTHING!
IT'S OKAY. SHH, SHH.
HEY, HEY, SHH.
NOTHING.
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KNOW. UM...
I KNOW.
I-I...
I HAVE TO FIGURE SOME,
YOU KNOW, SOME STUFF
BEFORE I CAN...
YEAH, I UNDERSTAND.
TAKE AS MUCH TIME
AS YOU WANT.
TEN, EVEN 20 MINUTES
IF YOU NEED IT.
I'LL BE HERE...
NOT SMOKING.
( knocking )
CHANDLER.
WHERE IS SHE?
I'M NOT SCARED OF YOU.
SHE'S NOT HERE
AND PLEASE COME IN.
SCOTCH ON THE ROCKS,
WITH A TWIST...
ON A COASTER--
( chuckles )
MONICA? MONICA?
OKAY, SHE WAS HERE,
BUT SHE LEFT.
WHERE DID SHE GO?
WELL, SHE SAID
SHE HAD TO THINK THINGS OVER.
OH, MY GOD.
I CAN'T BELIEVE THIS,
YOU KNOW?
I THOUGHT...
I THOUGHT YOU WERE A GOOD GUY.
OH, HEY, LOOK, NOTHING HAPPENED.
NOTHING HAPPENED? NOTHING?
SO YOU DIDN'T TELL MY GIRLFRIEND
THAT YOU LOVE HER?
WELL, ALL RIGHT,
ONE THING HAPPENED.
YOU KNOW, I CAN'T BELIEVE THIS.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU DID?
MY GIRLFRIEND IS
OUT THERE THINKING THINGS OVER.
YOU MADE MY GIRLFRIEND THINK!
WELL, I'M SORRY.
WHAT DOES SHE HAVE
TO THINK ABOUT?
I LOVE HER.
WELL, APPARENTLY I'M WILLING
TO OFFER HER THINGS
THAT YOU ARE NOT.
BUT I AM WILLING
TO OFFER HER ALL
THOSE THINGS.
THIS WAS JUST
A PLAN, YOU KNOW?
A WAY TO THROW HER
OFF COURSE
SO THAT WHEN I OFFERED
HER ALL THESE THINGS
SHE'D BE SURPRISED.
WELL, IF IT HELPS,
IT WORKED VERY WELL.
WELL, IT WAS WORKING
UNTIL YOU SHOWED UP
YOU BIG TREE.
I MEAN, THIS ISN'T FAIR.
YOU HAD YOUR CHANCE WITH HER.
YOU HAD YOUR CHANCE
AND YOU BLEW IT!
AND THIS IS MY CHANCE
AND I'M NOT GOING TO BLOW IT
BECAUSE WE ARE MEANT
FOR EACH OTHER.
AND THIS HAS ALL JUST BEEN
ONE STUPID MISTAKE.
I WAS GOING TO PROPOSE TONIGHT.
YOU WERE GOING TO PROPOSE?
YEAH, I EVEN...
GOT A RING.
DID YOU GET A RING?
NO, I DON'T HAVE A RING.
YOU GO GET HER, CHANDLER.
AND CAN I GIVE YOU
A PIECE OF ADVICE?
IF YOU DO GET HER...
DON'T LET HER GO.
TRUST ME.
YOU KNOW, RICHARD...
YOU ARE A GOOD GUY.
I KNOW.
I HATE THAT.
DUDE...
I CAN'T TALK TO YOU NOW.
I GOT TO FIND MONICA.
SHE'S GONE.
WHAT?
SHE HAD A BAG
AND SHE LEFT.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
SHE WAS ALL CRYING.
SHE SAID YOU GUYS
WANT DIFFERENT THINGS
AND THAT SHE NEEDED
TIME TO THINK.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL HER
IT WAS A PLAN?
I DID. I TOLD HER
EVERYTHING, CHANDLER
BUT SHE WOULDN'T BELIEVE ME.
WELL, WHERE...?
WHERE DID SHE GO?
TO HER PARENTS,
I THINK
AND SHE SAID THAT
YOU SHOULDN'T CALL HER
BUT IF I WERE YOU,
I WOULD.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I RUINED THIS.
I AM SO SORRY, MAN.
DAMN.
YOU WANTED IT
TO BE A SURPRISE.
OH, MY GOD.
CHANDLER, IN ALL MY LIFE
I NEVER THOUGHT
I WOULD BE SO LUCKY...
( voice breaking ):
AS TO FALL IN LOVE
WITH MY BEST...
MY BEST...
THERE'S A REASON WHY
GIRLS DON'T DO THIS!
OKAY, OKAY.
I'LL DO IT.
I THOUGHT...
I CAN DO THIS.
( chuckles )
I THOUGHT THAT IT MATTERED
WHAT I SAID
OR WHERE I SAID IT.
THEN I REALIZED
THE ONLY THING
THAT MATTERS IS THAT YOU...
YOU MAKE ME HAPPIER
THAN I EVER THOUGHT
I COULD BE.
AND IF YOU LET ME
I WILL SPEND
THE REST OF MY LIFE
TRYING TO MAKE YOU FEEL
THE SAME WAY.
( chuckles )
MONICA...
WILL YOU MARRY ME?
YES.
I KNEW YOU WERE LIKELY
TO TAKE A WIFE!
Joey:
CAN WE COME IN YET?!
WE'RE DYING OUT HERE!
COME IN! COME IN!
WE'RE ENGAGED!
( all cheering )
OH, THIS IS THE
LEAST JEALOUS
I'VE EVER BEEN!
OH, NO, WAIT! NO!
THIS IS WRONG!
ROSS ISN'T HERE!
OH.
OH, HELL, HE'S DONE
THIS THREE TIMES!
HE KNOWS WHAT
IT'S ABOUT!
YEAH!
COME ON, BABY!
HEY, HEY, HEY!
Captioned by
The Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]